three things I like about the
NordicTrack se9i are the thousands of
workouts available on the 14-inch
touchscreen monitor the automatic
adjustments that are going to take place
there in the middle of your workout and
its ability to fold and be stored
vertically I've been using this
elliptical for a while now and hang
tight because there's a lot to talk
about
[Music]
what's up everybody it's Jake back once
again in the barbing garage gym and this
time around I have the NordicTrack SE 9i
elliptical in the gym for review now in
this video I'm going to talk to you a
lot about the price the features some
pros and cons with this elliptical but
also you know who should or maybe should
not purchase one of these now before I
get going with all that I have to let
you know we've reviewed a ton of
ellipticals on barbin.com so if you want
to browse our best list just go and
search bar Bend best ellipticals and you
can find out for yourself which one
cracks that number one spot
foreign
[Music]
on what I like about the se9i elliptical
so first of all you cannot ignore the
fact that there are thousands of
workouts available from iFit on the 14
inch touchscreen monitor there's 24
levels of resistance to go along with 10
degrees of incline there's going to be
automatic adjustments during the middle
of your workout with both of those
variables which is really nice it's a
really cool feature there's a built-in
fan and a water bottle holder there's
Bluetooth capabilities for your
headphones or even a heart rate monitor
there's popular music loaded onto this
elliptical so you'll never be bored as
you're working out the manual
adjustments are crucial they're going to
come in handy as you're working out and
maybe you want to increase or decrease
the difficulty on your own you can
definitely do so plus a handle and a set
of wheels are going to make this
elliptical really portable and you can
also fold it in half and store it
vertically so you can make the absolute
most of your available space
foreign
okay so let's talk about a few potential
cons you might run into with this
elliptical I know I just got done saying
it can be folded and stored vertically
to make the most of your space that's
definitely still true but this also is
not a small elliptical but any means
necessary so it might dominate too much
space for some people which is you know
clearly a bummer the stride length is 18
inches and you know if you're under six
feet tall it's not going to be a problem
for you but if you are six feet or
taller you might not be able to stretch
out as much as you'd like so definitely
keep that in mind the flywheel also
weighs 18 pounds you know that's not too
terrible in my opinion but you know some
people may not be too crazy about that
kind of had to be done though you know
for it to be foldable and also as
portable as it is the two handlebars in
front of the monitor can kind of get in
the way at certain times especially you
know as you're going to use those manual
adjustments that are located just
underneath that monitor the cup holder
is also a little bit smaller than what I
would personally like you know not every
single water bottle is going to be able
to fit in there you can't really adjust
the height of the monitor itself at all
you can tilt it a little bit but you
know if you are on the taller side of
things you know you might have to Crane
your neck just a little bit you know
it's not too bad but definitely keep
that in mind it's also definitely not
cheap now it's on sale right now for
about 1500 bucks but you can typically
expect it to run you around Seventeen
hundred dollars and you know like I said
that's not really cheap so if you want a
cheaper you know elliptical maybe a more
basic one there's definitely some other
options out there you know for you to
take a good look at and on top of that
you know after that free month of iFit
runs out with your purchase you're gonna
have to pay a monthly membership fee or
maybe even one of the three yearly
options to choose from so it's just more
money you have to spend and obviously
you know you're gonna need a pretty good
Wi-Fi connection just to load all of the
classes that are available on this
Monitor and also you know in terms of
buffering and making sure you get a nice
picture during your workout
okay so let's talk about price a little
bit now once again the se9i is available
for right around 1500 bucks right now
because it's on sale but typically you
can expect it to run you around
Seventeen hundred dollars now that's
definitely not cheap right so you know
if you want a more basic elliptical
maybe you don't care about streaming
your workouts and you know all the other
luxury features that are on this luxury
product you might be better off saving
some money you know especially if you're
not going to use it very frequently but
if you are planning on using it a lot
you do care about those you know added
features I definitely think it's going
to be worth the money you know this is a
top of the line product and that's felt
every single time that you hop on it now
you can definitely Finance this purchase
if you want to but you know what you pay
monthly is going to be directly impacted
based on whether or not you want to add
on one of those three yearly iFit
membership plans or maybe even an
extended warranty plan but the cool
thing is NordicTrack is going to
calculate all that for you and they're
going to provide a couple different
payment plans for you to choose from
now let's talk about one of my favorite
things about this elliptical and really
with all of nordictrack's equipment is
the availability to over 16
000 workout classes through ifis this is
awesome in my opinion now I mean
obviously you know there's plenty of
classes you can have for this elliptical
but you know with your iFit membership
you also have access to strength
training classes yoga classes meditation
I mean the list goes on and on and on
cool thing is you can hop in a studio
class you know get that actual Studio
feel with the personal trainer and some
other workout members as well or you can
even travel the world I mean different
parts of the world that you may not even
ever really have the chance to go to
this honestly is my favorite thing I
went on a walk through the Balkans the
other day and I thought it was really
cool how the automatic adjustments took
place you know according to the actual
trail that we were going on I think
you'll like that too but you cannot
forget about the companion app and this
is going to be really nice you know
especially for anybody who cares about
joining their strength training classes
and all the other ones that are
available available as I was just
mentioning it's also a really great
place to track all your stats you know
your weekly monthly yearly workouts and
you know keep track of your goals and
also just overall progress there's a
calendar tab it's going to show you all
your completed workouts you've recently
done it's a challenge tab where you can
see the challenges you've completed you
can also click on the Discover challenge
button and check out all the challenges
that are available there's always new
ones that are being added that's really
cool you know they're going to be
varying based off of your product that
you're using you know any type of
strength training equipment that you're
using there's a lot of different options
out there for you so you're always
pushing yourself there's also
leaderboards with all that as well you
can check out and kind of you know go
head to head with other people and
anybody who thrives off that competition
like I tend to do I think you're really
going to like that
okay so let's spend some time talking
about the technology with this high-tech
piece of equipment so all of NordicTrack
stuff operates on Android os9 technology
so it's definitely up to date you have a
14 inch touchscreen monitor that can
tilt a little bit you also have two two
inch speakers located just above the
monitor they all honestly provide a
really solid sound you have Bluetooth
capabilities for your headphones or
heart rate monitor all of nordictrack's
equipment also uses Google Maps which is
really cool you can pick any city in the
world and you know create your own
course your own workout whatever you
want to call it you can even use that
Google street cam View and get a sense
of you know you're actually in the city
which is you know pretty cool in my
opinion you have automatic adjustments
that are going to take place you're in
the middle of your workout with your
resistance and your incline and the
motor that powers both of those is
honestly relatively quiet and of course
you cannot forget about that built-in
fan as you start to work up a sweat
[Music]
now when it comes to the build and a
little bit more about those features we
got to talk about the framework first
it's definitely made from steel it feels
really durable feels really stable in my
opinion it's about 67 inches tall around
80 inches long about 32 inches wide and
it weighs a hefty 220 pounds so
thankfully you do have that handle and
two sets of Wheels it's going to make it
pretty easy to move around your personal
space it has a 325 pound weight limit
which is honestly you know it's a pretty
high number right there you also have a
10 year warranty on the frame that's
really nice you know it's a nice safety
blanket you know you know you're going
to be taken care of if anything were to
happen to it the 14 inch touchscreen
monitor does tilt a little bit and it's
also going to track all of your stats so
your distance your speed resistant level
incline level all of that is going to be
right there on the monitor it's also
going to estimate your calories burned
but if you do pair up your heart rate
monitor it's going to be exact and show
you you know exactly how much you've
burned and currently are burning that's
definitely going to come in handy
because there is not any type of heart
rate sensor built into the elliptical
itself you also have automatic
adjustments that are going to take place
here in the middle of your workout but
you can also manually adjust that as
well if you need to you can you know
adjust the built-in fan speed and your
volume speed can't forget about that cup
holder either you know remember it is a
little bit smaller than what some people
may like and it might not fit every
single water bottle
all right so let's go ahead and do a
walk around with this elliptical and
kind of demonstrate how everything
operates so in the back right here is
where your power cord gets plugged in
really simple just plug it in that
monitor is going to come right on for
you now this is a 18 pound flywheel a
lot of times you know flywheels are 20
pounds it's going to add a little bit
more resistance but you know the ability
to fold and be as portable kind of you
know required at 18 pound flywheel now
let's move a little further up right
here starting with your pedals it's
actually pretty cool these can be
adjusted so you pull out back here on
this plastic piece and there's three
different heights they can be you know
tilted to just for your own Comfort
level you know that's really nice this
is a 18 inch stride and you know
somebody under six feet tall it's gonna
be perfect for you I think but if you
are six feet or taller you might not be
able to you know stretch out as much as
you personally would like as we move on
up this is that cup holder
as you can see you know it is a little
bit smaller than you know what you might
like it's not going to fit every single
water bottle but you know your basic
water bottle is going to be just fine
these arms move as you're working out
you know and that's nice you also have
some automatic excuse me manual
adjustments that are located on the top
of those handles right there which is
really cool I'm not too crazy about
these two handles right here in front of
the monitor because as you can see they
kind of get in the way especially with
these manual adjustments down here and
even some of the monitor itself it can
be a little bit tricky you know just to
reach everything and navigate through
the menus but you know overall with this
monitor it's really nice you know the
touch screen's super easy to use you
simply scroll through and there's as you
can see I mean there's so many workouts
for you to do the font might be kind of
hard to read right now but at the bottom
you know we're on the Home tab there's a
calendar where it's going to show you
all your recent workouts you've
completed which is really cool
I mean it's just all going to be right
there if you want to do them again you
got to create tab there's a browse tab
trophy case it's going to show your
completed challenges you've done there's
a lot going on right here you can go
back to the home page and you can you
know you can edit the appearance you can
turn it into a dark mode or a light mode
we have it on now you can also invite up
to four different users to share your
membership plan so you can technically
have five different people under one
account which is really nice and you can
split everything up money wise if you
want to now coolest thing about this
elliptical is its ability to fold and be
stored vertically so I'm going to show
you how to do that so there's this knob
right here mine's already untwisted just
want to untwist it pull out on it
there's a tab back here you want to pull
up on
and then you just lower it down like so
and then now you know especially once
you have it unplugged which I don't have
unplugged right now it's a handle right
here on the front you simply use this
lift up on it and on the back I meant to
show you this a second ago but you do
have a pair of feet on either side just
like that right there that way you can
store it vertically in a corner of a
room or whatever and make the most of
your available space
all right so let's talk about those who
might want to purchase the se9i well if
you're tight on Space you know maybe you
just want an elliptical that allows you
to make the most of your available space
I think you're really going to like the
fact that you can fold this elliptical
and store it vertically if you're
somebody who wants some trainer-led
classes I think you're going to love the
integration of iFit and piggybacking off
that because of all of those classes
that are available you're going to have
those automatic adjustments based on
each individual workout and that's
really nice because you're never going
to get bored and you're never going to
get complacent since no workout is going
to be the same
[Music]
all right so let's talk about those who
might not want to purchase this
elliptical now so let's talk about the
money first you know 1500 is still
fifteen hundred dollars so if you're not
going to be dedicated to using this
elliptical at least you know multiple
times a week you might be better off you
know looking for a cheaper option and
you know kind of sticking with that if
you don't care about all the luxury
features with this elliptical you know
the automatic adjustments the
trainer-led classes on that 14 inch
touchscreen monitor I think you might be
better off looking for a cheaper option
anyway it's more basic and then lastly
is available space yeah this is
considered a space saver still true you
can still fold it and store it
vertically but it still might dominate
too much space for you know some people
so if you're kind of tight on Space you
might want to look for a smaller option
as well
[Music]
that's all I have for you guys today on
the NordicTrack
se9i I honestly think this is an awesome
elliptical you know it's great for
people like myself who want a low impact
way to get their cardio in plus it's a
great option worth considering for
anyone who wants a personal trainer feel
with their workouts it is a little bit
pricey and you know it's still going to
dominate a good amount of space but you
can always store it vertically in the
luxury features here are likely going to
make this well worth the money in the
long run thanks for watching y'all I
hope this video was really helpful and
that I was able to answer any questions
you may have about this product as
always stay posted for my next video but
for now head over to barbin.com you can
read more about this elliptical all you
got to do is search bar Bend NordicTrack
space saver se9i review you'll find all
the details and everything I discussed
here today is going to be in that
article I'll catch y'all next time
[Music]
foreign